[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
One of the most common types of classifiers is a so
最常见的一种分类器
called linear classifier.
是线性分类器
So let's talk a little bit about that.
那么 让我们来多了解一点
The question here is how do we represent the classifier?
这里的问题是 怎么来表示分类器呢
So we start with some sentences, for example in a sentiment the mouse's case,
我们从一些句子入手 比如 我们情感分类那个例子中
the classifier.
这个分类器
You get a prediction whether it is a positive sentence or a negative sentence.
你预测这个语句是积极的 还是消极的
So, how does this classifier work?
这个分类器是怎么工作的呢？
In the sentimental analysis you can imagine a simple
在这个情感分析的例子中 你可以想象一个简单的
kind of threshold classifier.
阈值分类器
Suppose that I take a sentence and somebody tells me
假设我们输入一条语句 有人告诉我
these are all of the positive words, great, awesome, good amazing and so on.
这个句子里都是积极的单词 比如说 极好的 非常棒的 令人惊喜的 等等
Here's a bunch of negative words.
同样 这里有一堆消极单词的集合
Bad, terrible, disgusting, food, and so on.
比如 坏的 极差的 令人作呕的食物 等等
And so what I can do is take the sentence and
我现在可以做的就是 输入这条语句
count how many positive words there are in a sentence and
计数这个句子中有多少个积极的单词
how many negative words are in the sentence, just count those.
有多少个消极的单词
And then say if the number of positive words is higher
如果积极单词的数目
than the number of negative words.
比消极单词的数目多
Then we have a positive sentence but
这个就是一个积极的语句
if they use more negative more words then you have a negative sentence.
如果消极的单词比积极的多 这就是一个消极的语句
So for example, if the input sentence that we have is the sushi was great positive
举个例子，如果输入语句是 这里有最棒的寿司（一个积极单词“great”）
one, the food was awesome positive two, but the service was terrible negative one.
这里的食物非常棒（第二个积极单词“awesome”） 但是这里的服务很糟糕（一个消极单词“terrible”）
You have two positives one negative and
有两个积极的单词和一个消极的单词
in the end was the positive wins and so you have a positive prediction.
消极的单词数目多 因此给出一个积极的预测
Now threshold classifiers have some limitations.
阈值分类器有一些局限
Where does this list of positive and negative words actually come from?
这些积极和消极的单词实际上是从哪获得的？
It has to magically come from somewhere and
他们从某个地方就这么神奇的出现了
not just that, words have different degrees of positive and negativeness.
不仅如此 这些单词代表的积极和消极的程度也不同
So great is more positive than good.
“great”比“good”的词性更积极
You wanna tune and figure out what's better great, good, amazing,
你想要知道“great”，“good”，“amazing”哪个词性更强
is amazing better than great?
“amazing”的词性要比“great”强吗？
Who knows?
谁知道呢?
So how do we figure that out, how do we weigh different words?
我们怎么来考虑不同单词的权重呢
And single words might not be enough to make good classification.
单个的单词无法用来做好分类
So good food, so the food was good is positive.
就拿“good"来说 食物是好的 是积极的语句
The food was not good is actually negative.
食物是不好（”not good“）的 就是消极的语句了
And so these are all issues that need to be addressed.
这些问题都是需要考虑进去的
The first two areas where the positive and negative words come from and
积极和消极的单词表从哪获得
how do you weigh them comes from learning a classifier and
我们怎么对他们进行权值分配 是学习分类器的首要两个任务
we're going to talk about next.
我们后面会进行讨论
The issue of good versus not good
解决像“good”和“not good”这样的问题
is addressed by using more complicated features than single words.
需要考虑更复杂的特征 而不是基于单个单词
And we're gonna talk about it towards the end of the module.
我们在章节的最后会进行讨论
So a linear classifier, instead of having a list of positive and
线性分类器 不是简单地获取一个积极和
negative words, actually takes all the words and adds weights to them.
消极单词的列表 而是对他们加入权值
So, for example, good might have a weight of 1, great might have a weight of 1.5,
例如，“good”也许会有一个1的权值 而“great”也许会有一个1.5的权值
awesome might have really big weight of 2.7.
“awesome”也许会有一个更大的权值2.7
While bad might have a weight of -1, terrible may have a weight of -2.1,
而“bad”也许会有一个-1的权值 “terrible”也许会有一个-2.1的权值
awful might be -3.3 cuz awful is really just awful.
“awful”也许会有一个-3.3的权值 “awful”确实很糟糕
And this ways that really don't matter to sentiment.
用这种方式 “really”与情感无关
So things like the, we, where, restaurant, they appear both in positive and
同样的 “the”，“we”，“where”，“restaurant”这些单词既出现在积极语句
negative sentences so they get weight zero.
也出现在消极的语句中 因此他们的权值为0
Suppose somebody magically told you what the weight of each word were.
假设有人告诉你所有单词的权值
We're going to talk about it in a little bit how those get learned
我们来讨论一下怎么利用这些单词和权值
by the classifier.
训练分类器
But given those weight, how to figure out if the sentence is positive or negative.
给定这些单词的权值 我们要确定一个句子是积极的还是消极的
Here we use the idea of scoring.
我们这里用的是评分的思想
So for example take this sentence.
拿这个句子为例
The sushi was great, the food was awesome, but the service was terrible.
寿司很好 食物非常棒 但是服务比较糟糕
Let's score that sentence.
我们来对这个句子进行评分
So we're gonna compute this, the score of the input sentence x.
我们来计算一下 输入语句x的评分
So in this case, you get from great, you get positive 1.2.
在这个例子中 “great”的权值是+1.2
From awesome, you get another 1.7 but
“awesome”的权值是1.7
from table, you get minus 2.1 right here,
“terrible”的权值是-2.1
and so the grand total here is 2.9 minus 2.1, which is 0.8.
因此最后的评分是 2.9 - 2.1 结果是0.8
And the key here is that since the score of the sentence is greater than zero,
这个句子的评分比0大
we're going to predict that it is a positive sentence.
我们将预测这个句子为积极的语句
If the score was the opposite, if the score of x were less than zero,
如果评分是负的 输入x的评分小于0
then we'd have predicted it's a negative sentence.
我们就预测这个句子是消极的语句
So this is how a linear classifier works,
分类器就是这样工作的
if you know the weight of each word, and this is called
如果你知道每一个单词的权值 这个分类器就叫做
a linear classifier because the output is basically the weighted sum of the input.
线性分类器 因为输出是输入的权值的简单求和
Just weight, what features appears, what words appear in the input.
仅仅是权值而已 不管出现什么样的特征 不管出现什么样的单词
So we're working for simple linear classifier to start out with.
我们从这个简单的线性分类器开始讨论
So in summary, given a sentence and given the weights for
总之 给定一句话 和单词的权值
the sentence, what we do is compute the score,
我们可以计算这句话的评分
which is the weighted count of the words that appear in the sentence.
评分由出现在句子中的权值之和计算而来
And then we say if the score is greater than zero,
然后我们看一下这个评分是否大于0
we predict y-hat to be positive.
如果大于0我们就预测输出是正类
While if the score is less than zero, we predict it to be negative.
如果评分小于0 我们就预测为负类
And that is a linear classifier.
这就是线性分类器
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community